Mikael Röthig

Skilled software developer with a passion for crafting user-friendly experiences. I excel in front-end development, bringing clean code and visually appealing designs to life, ensuring a seamless and engaging user journey across all devices.

mrrothig@gmail.com +27 (0) 79 610 1478 github.com/mikaelrothig linkedin.com/in/mikaelrothig mikaelrothig.com

RELEVANT EXPERIENCE

Junior Web Developer · Positive Digits Apr 2023 - Sep 2024

- Designed and executed a multi-language, multi domain lead generation site as part of a two person team using Sulu, Tailwind CSS, and Stimulus JS.
- Contributed to the ongoing maintenance of a web shop with 100,000 products, working alongside a mentor to keep product information accurate and the site running efficiently.
- Created clean and efficient front-end designs for clients and in house websites.

IT Support · Cape Town Engineering Jan 2017 - Mar 2020

- Provided technical support and troubleshooted a variety of hardware and software issues.
- Conducted routine maintenance and system updates of the office computers.

EDUCATION

BCIS in Game Design & Development

Vega School Cape Town Jan 2017- Dec 2019

- Learned to develop games using the Unity engine and C#.
- Designed and modeled 3D game assets using Blender.
- Represented Vega at the Cape Town Electronic Games Exhibition in 2017 and 2018.

SKILLS

Programming Languages

Javascript, Typescript, HTML, CSS, SCSS, PHP, C#

Libraries & Frameworks

Symfony, Shopware, Sulu, Hugo, Astro, Tailwind CSS, Stimulus JS

Tools & Platforms

Git, Github, Adobe XD, Adobe Illustrator, Adobe Photoshop, Figma, Unity, Blender, Vercel

SELECTED PROJECTS

Weather Station Dashboard

Weather app for Kite Beach in Cape Town that aggregates data from multiple sources. Built with React, Tailwind CSS, and designed in Figma.

mikaelrothig.com

Personal website built with Astro and Tailwind CSS.

LANGUAGES

English (Native) • Dutch (Elementary) • German (Elementary)

INTERESTS

Football • Kitesurfing • Gaming & PC hardware/software • Exploring new tech • Traveling